Demi Lovato: Simply Complicated is a music,
documentary film directed by Hannah Lux Davis.
A personal and intimate look into Demi Lovato's life as not only a regular 25
year old, but also one of the biggest pop stars in the world.
Self, played by Demi Lovato.
Self, played by Dallas Lovato.
Self, played by Madison De La Garza.
Self, played by Wilmer Valderrama.
Self, played by Nick Jonas.
Self, played by Joe Jonas.
Demi Lovato: Simply Complicated is a 2017 documentary film about the life and career of American singer, songwriter, and actor
Demi Lovato, released on YouTube on October 17, 2017 in support of her sixth studio album Tell Me You Love Me.
A director's cut of the documentary including 10 minutes of additional
footage was later released on YouTube Premium in December 2017.
Simply Complicated chronicles both the recording of Tell Me You Love Me as well as events in Lovato's life and career that she had not previously disclosed or
discussed extensively, including the beginning of her career on Disney Channel and various personal struggles with mental health and addiction.
Lovato also admitted to being dishonest about the initial outcome of her recovery in a previous documentary, Demi Lovato: Stay Strong
(2012), and revealed she was in fact under the influence of cocaine while being interviewed about her sobriety for that film.